Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5863 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 13)
  - 0892. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Price, James. 90 pages., 1922-1924; 25 (Reel 13)
    People: James Price; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Augustus T. Seymour; Earl J. Davis; James A. Finch; Robert Duncan; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Warren F. Martin; Harry M. Daugherty; Harry Feinberg. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Industrial Workers of the World publications; California state criminal syndicalism law convictions; General Defense Committee.
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 14)
  - 0001. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Connor, Roy P. 154 pages., 1920-1923; 1 (Reel 14)
    People: Roy P. Connor; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Roger N. Baldwin; Newton D. Baker; Thomas W. Hardwick; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Clifford Walker; Thomas W. Hardwick; Robert Duncan; John W. Preston; Frank H. Rudkin; George Wharton Pepper; William E. Borah. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen and United States congressman protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union; hunger strikes.
  - 0155. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. 234 pages., 1918-1923; 2 (Reel 14)
    People: George Wharton Pepper; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Frank M. Silva; Robert Duncan; John W. Preston; P.H. Johnson; William D. Stephens; Charles M. Fickert; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; F.W. Henshaw; Harry M. Daugherty; Augustus T. Seymour; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California, and Chicago, Illinois, and recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; citizen and United States congressman protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union publications regarding Industrial Workers of the World cases; Mooney-Billings case; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California; Joint Amnesty Committee. File folder omitted.
  - 0389. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Previously Restricted Materials. 112 pages., 1922-1974; 3 (Reel 14)
    People: Richard S. Street; James A. Finch; William J. Burns. Subjects: Request for access to Department of Justice files regarding Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World prosecutions; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Bureau of Investigation reports on executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0501. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. General. 23 pages., 1922-1923; 4 (Reel 14)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0524. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. 88 pages., 1920-1923; 5 (Reel 14)
    People: C.W. Anderson; Fred Robertson; Hendrik Shipstead; Knute Nelson; Frank B. Kellogg; James A. Finch; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Harry M. Daugherty; Roger N. Baldwin; Oscar E. Gordon. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen and United States congressman protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union. File folder omitted.
  - 0612. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Anderson, C.W. 244 pages., 1918-1976; 6 (Reel 14)
    People: C.W. Anderson; Michael Sapper; Oscar E. Gordon; F.J. Gallagher; Wencil Francik; Phineas Eastman; Samuel B. Amidon; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty; Augustus T. Seymour; John C. Pollock; Robert P. Stewart; Robert H. Turner; Warren G. Harding; James A. Finch; Fred Robertson; Thomas J. Howe. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; decision, petition for rehearing, and petition for writ of error before the United States Circuit Court of Appeals in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; indictment in United States Court in case against C.W. Anderson, et al.; requests for access to Department of Justice files relating to Industrial Workers of the World cases. File folder omitted.
  - 0856. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Francik, Wencil. 40 pages., 1922-1923; 7 (Reel 14)
    People: Wencil Francik; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0896. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Francik, Wencil. Previously Restricted Materials. 6 pages., 1923; 8 (Reel 14)
    People: Wencil Francik; James A. Finch. Subjects: Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Bureau of Investigation.
  - 0902. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Gallagher, F.J. 50 pages., 1920-1923; 9 (Reel 14)
    People: F.J. Gallagher; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred Robertson; Samuel B. Amidon; Caroline A. Lowe; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0952. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Sapper, Michael. 38 pages., 1923; 10 (Reel 14)
    People: Michael Sapper; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 15)
  - 0001. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Anderson, C.W. et al. Kansas City Industrial Workers of the World. 1129 pages., 1919 (Reel 15)
    People: C.W. Anderson; John C. Pollock; Fred Robertson; Samuel B. Amidon; Fred H. Moore; Caroline A. Lowe. Subjects: Transcript of trial in case against C.W. Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice prosecution of Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World defendants; lists of exhibits, indexes, arguments, testimony, charge of the court, verdicts, and sentences in case before the United States District Court for the District of Kansas. File folder omitted. December 1-18, 1919.